creativepool.co.uk 2018-10-20

# Privacy Statement | Creativepool

. . .

_**Overview**_

Our primary goal in collecting personal information is to provide you with a safe, efficient, and personalised experience. We only collect personal information about you that we consider necessary for this purpose.  

Our services connect people across the globe to allow for a fully interactive network within the Creative industry. As a result your interactions with other members / companies on Creativepool are public by default, along with some of your personal information, such as your name.  

This Privacy Policy describes to you how and when we will collect, use and share your information. When using any of our services you consent to the collection, transfer, storage, disclosure, and use of your information as described in this Privacy Policy. This will include any information you choose to provide that is deemed sensitive under applicable laws. Throughout this Privacy Policy, the terms “we” or “us” refer to Creativepool Ltd (company reg 05707888). Creativepool Ltd is the “Controller” and “Processor” of your information under current data law.  

As a website we are constantly improving our services, which means we get new data and create new ways to use data. Our services are dynamic, and we often introduce new features, which may require the collection of new information. If we collect materially different personal data or materially change how we use your data, we will notify you and may also modify this Privacy Policy.  

If we decide to change our Privacy Policy, you will be notified either through your account or sent an email, or both. We will update the changes here so that you will always know what information we gather, how we might use that information, and whether we will disclose it to anyone. If you have questions or concerns about Creativepool’s Privacy Policy, please feel free to email Support https://creativepool.com/contactus.php 

_**Information about Creativepool Visitors**_

In general, we gather information about all of our non-registered visitors collectively, such as what areas users visit and what services our users access. We only use such data in the aggregate, ie. no personal information specific to a user will be included. This information helps us determine what is most beneficial for our users and how we can continually create a better overall experience for you. If we do share this information with third parties it will only be in the aggregate, so that our external partners may understand how Creativepool users, collectively, use our site, so they may create a better overall experience for you too.

 _ **Information about Creativepool Members**_  
A member of Creativepool is someone who registers on the site and creates a profile for either a Company or as an individual.  

You have choices about the information on your profile, such as your education, work experience, skills, photo, city or area. You don’t have to provide additional information on your profile; however, profile information helps you to get more from our services, including helping recruitment consultants, hiring companies and business opportunities find you. It’s your choice whether to include sensitive information on your profile and to make that sensitive information public. As an individual you have the choice to make your profile 1. Public (on the web), Public (just on Creativepool), Hidden everywhere. Hidden everywhere will still mean that we hold your data but that it will not be seen by users of the site. To keep your data safe we recommend the you do not post or add personal data to your profile regardless of this setting that you would not want to be publicly available.  

To create an account you need to provide data including your name, address, email address and/or phone number(s), and a password. If you are an individual member and applying for a role advertised on the site then you will need to provide additional information at the bequest of the advertiser these may include but are not limited to Your Contact Details, uploading your CV/Resume, adding a profile image, specifying your Education Level, the Industry you work in, your Skills and Sector Experience and ask you to fill out your "Get Listed" data. All of this information will be passed on to the advertiser and may also be accessed by anyone who is using the site for finding talent and comes across your profile. You will be notified by email if anyone downloads your CV/Resume.  

If you register for a premium Service, you will need to provide payment (e.g., credit card) and billing information. We store your personal information securely, and use it to provide you with our services. We use external partners for processing payments (Optimal Payments / Elavon Financial Services / American Express / Paypal). We do not store credit card details nor do we share financial details with any 3rd parties.

 _ **Data From Others**_  

Content and News  
You and others may post content that includes information about you (as part of articles for example) on our services. Unless you opt-out, we may collect this public information about you, and make it available as part of our services.  

Customers and partners may provide data to us.  

Partners and Other Companies  

We receive personal data about you when you use the services of our customers and partners, such as employers, prospective employers and applicant tracking systems providing us job application data. We receive data about you when you use some of the other services provided by us or our affiliates.

 _ **Communications**_  

We will contact you through email, post, phone, notices posted on our website, messages to your Creativepool inbox, and other ways through our services. We will send you messages about the availability of our services, security, or other service-related issues. We also send messages about how to use the services, network updates, reminders, job suggestions and promotional messages from us and our partners. You may change your communication preferences at any time.   

We process personal information for certain legitimate business purposes, which include some or all of the following:  
Where the processing enables us to enhance, modify, personalise or otherwise improve our services / communications for the benefit of our members  
To identify and prevent fraud  
To enhance the security of our network and information systems   
To better understand how people interact with Creativepool  
To provide communications which we think will be of interest to you during use of our services (relevant job notifications/networking opportunities/events and awards which would be of interest to you based on the information you have provided)  
To determine the effectiveness of promotional campaigns and advertising

Whenever we process data for these purposes we will ensure that we always keep your personal data rights in high regard and take account of these rights. You have the right to object to this processing if you wish, and if you wish to do so please click https://creativepool.com/privacy/. Please bear in mind that if you do object to this processing, it may affect our ability to carry out tasks for your benefit.  

Please be aware that you cannot opt-out of receiving service messages from us, including security and legal notices.  

We also enable communications between you and others through our services.

 _ **Marketing**_  

We promote our services to you and others.  

We use data and content about Members for invitations and communications promoting membership and network growth, engagement and our services.

We use your personal information to to promote to you, and enable you to enter competitions, and to send you emails that contain promotions on behalf of our third party partners and event sponsors, 

_**Developing services and Research**_  

We develop our services and conduct research.  

Service Development

We use data, including public feedback, to conduct research and development for the further development of our services in order to provide you and others with a better, more intuitive and personalized experience, drive membership growth and engagement on our services, and help connect professionals to each other and to economic opportunity.  

Customer Support  

We use data (which can include your communications) to investigate, respond to and resolve complaints and service issues.

 _ **General information disclosure**_  

We do not disclose information about your individual visits to Creativepool, or any personal information that you provide, to any outside parties, except when we believe the law requires it. We may record and share depersonalised aggregated information with our partners. If you input your information on a co-branded registration page Creativepool is not responsible for the information that the partner company receives, you should check their privacy policy to ensure your data is safe.

 _ **CV's and Resume's**_  

By signing up with Creativepool you are given the opportunity to put your CV/Resume on your profile. This means that any registered employer will have access to your CV/Resume. You have control over how much of your personal contact information is available for viewing. A valid email address is the minimum contact information you must display. We use our best efforts to grant access to this database only to hiring employers. We are not responsible if some other third party evades security measures and gains access to the database, and, subsequently, your CV/Resume. You may remove your CV/Resume from our searchable database at any time. However, recruiters who have paid for access to the database may have retained a copy of your CV/Resume in their own files or databases. We are not responsible for the retention, use, or privacy of CV/Resume in these instances.

 _ **Reviews and comments**_  

Creativepool has areas on the site where you can submit reviews and comments. Any reviews and comments that are submitted through these areas are greatly appreciated and an important way for you to help us make Creativepool a better site. Any reviews and comments become the property of Creativepool and we reserve the right to use the information as we see fit, including using it for marketing of the site, unless you opt out or specifically request we remove your review / comment and all personal data related to it. You can do so by emailing support@creativepool.com 

_**Your password**_  

You are responsible for all actions taken with your User ID and password. We do not recommend that you disclose your Creativepool password to any third parties. If you lose control of your password, you may lose substantial control over your personally identifiable information and may be subject to legally binding actions taken on your behalf. Therefore, if your password or account has been compromised for any reason, you should immediately change your password. We do not know or store you password, but if you need to reset it you can do so here https://creativepool.com/privacy/.

 _ **Accessing, reviewing and changing your personal Information.**_  

All the personal information you provide to Creativepool can be reviewed and edited at any stage just by logging on to the site using your username and password. We offer you the ability to review and change the information you submit to us by logging into the site and entering in the new information yourself https://creativepool.com/profile/manage/. Generally, we will not modify your personal information based on your request because it is very difficult for us to authenticate your account manually. You must promptly update your personal information if it changes or is inaccurate. Once posted, you may not be able to change or remove any public postings made on the site including our review and forum areas.

 _ **Data Retention**_  

We retain your personal data while your account is in existence or as needed to provide you services. This includes data you or others provided to us and data generated or inferred from your use of our services. Even if you only use our services when looking for a new job every few years, we will retain your information and keep your profile open until you decide to close your account. In some cases we choose to retain certain information in a depersonalized or aggregated form. If your account is inactive, and doesn’t contain much information (ie a blank profile), we may retain your information for 5 years before removing it from our platform and our records.  

Delete Data: You can ask us to erase or delete all or some of your personal data  

Change or Correct Data: You can edit some of your personal data through your account. You can also ask us to change, update or fix your data in certain cases, particularly if it’s inaccurate.  

Object to, or Limit or Restrict, Use of Data: You can ask us to stop using all or some of your personal data, or to limit our use of it.  

Right to Access and/or Take Your Data: You can ask us for a copy of your personal data provided in machine readable form. Creativepool will provide the data to you within 30 days of your request

You can make any of the above requests by emailing dpo@creativepool.com

 _ **Account Closure**_  

If you choose to close your Creativepool account, your personal data will stop being visible to others on our services immediately. Account information is deleted at the same except as noted below. However your data may still be indexed by search engines such as google and as such some of your information will appear in search results until such time as the search engine provider indexes the page again and updates it’s results.  

We retain your personal data even after you have closed your account if reasonably necessary to comply with our legal obligations (including law enforcement requests), meet regulatory requirements, resolve disputes, maintain security, prevent fraud and abuse, enforce our User Agreement, or fulfill your request to “unsubscribe” from further messages from us. We will retain de-personalized information after your account has been closed.  

Information you have shared with others will remain visible after you closed your account or deleted the information from your own profile or mailbox, and we do not control data that other Members copied out of our services. Groups content and ratings or review content associated with closed accounts will show an unknown user as the source. Your profile may continue to be displayed in the services of others (e.g., search engine results) until they refresh their cache.

 _ **Cookies**_  

We use data collection devices such as "cookies" on certain pages of the Site. "Cookies" are small files placed on your hard drive that assist us in providing customised services. We offer certain features that are only available through the use of a cookie. We also use cookies to allow you to enter your password less frequently while you are using the site. Cookies can also help us provide information which we tailor to your interests. Most cookies are "session cookies", meaning that they are automatically deleted from your hard drive at the end of a session using the site. You are always free to decline our cookies if your browser permits, although in that case you may not be able to use certain features on the site and you may be required to re-enter your password more frequently while you are using the site.

When you visit or leave our services, we receive the URL of both the site you came from and the one you go to next. We also get information about your IP address, proxy server, operating system, web browser and add-ons, device identifier and features, and/or ISP or your mobile carrier. If you use our services from a mobile device, that device will send us data about your location based on your phone settings. We will ask you to opt-in before we use GPS or other tools to identify your precise location.

 _ **Security**_  

We monitor and try to prevent security breaches.   

Creativepool implements security safeguards designed to protect your data, such as HTTPS, encryption, and where applicable Secure Socket Layers. We regularly monitor our systems for possible vulnerabilities and attacks. However, we cannot warrant the security of any information that you send us.There is no guarantee that data may not be accessed, disclosed, altered, or destroyed by breach of any of our physical, technical, or managerial safeguards.We treat data as an asset that must be protected against loss and unauthorised access. We employ many different security techniques to protect such data from unauthorised access by users inside and outside the company. 

_**Cross-Border Data Transfers**_  

We process data both inside and outside of the United Kingdom and rely on legally-provided mechanisms to lawfully transfer data across borders. Countries where we process data may have laws which are different, and potentially not as protective, as the laws of your own country.

 _ **Lawful Bases for Processing**_  

At any time, you can withdraw consent you have provided by going to https://creativepool.com/privacy/ .  

We will collect and process personal data about you where we have lawful bases. Lawful bases include consent (where you have given consent), contract (where processing is necessary for the performance of a contract with you, and “legitimate interests”.  

Where we rely on your consent to process personal data, you have the right to withdraw or decline your consent at any time and where we rely on legitimate interests, you have the right to object. If you have any questions about the lawful bases upon which we collect and use your personal data, please contact our Data Protection Officer at dpo@creativepool.com 

_**Children**_  

Our services are not available to children and we ask that persons under the age of 18 do not submit any personal information to us. If you are under 18 years old, you cannot use this site. This is less to do with content that is sensitive to younger viewers and more to do with the fact that anyone under 18 is highly unlikely to have the skill set required to join Creativepool.

 _ **Posts, Likes, Follows, Comments, Messages**_  

Our services allow viewing and sharing information including through posts, likes, follows and comments.  

When you share an article or a post publicly it can be viewed by everyone and re-shared anywhere. Members, Visitors and others will be able to find and see your publicly-shared content, including your name (and photo if you have provided one).  

When you follow a person or organization, you are visible to others and that “page owner” as a follower.

 _ **Related services**_  

We share your data across our different services and Creativepool-affiliated entities.  

We will share your personal data with our affiliates to provide and develop our services. We may combine information internally across the different services covered by this Privacy Policy to help our services be more relevant and useful to you and others. 

_**Service Providers**_  

We may use others to help us with our services.  

We use others to help us provide our services (e.g., maintenance, analysis, audit, payments, fraud detection, marketing and development). They will have access to your information as reasonably necessary to perform these tasks on our behalf and are obligated not to disclose or use it for other purposes.

 _ **Legal Disclosures**_  

We may need to share your data when we believe it’s required by law or to help protect the rights and safety of you, us or others.  

It is possible that we will need to disclose information about you when required by law, subpoena, or other legal process or if we have a good faith belief that disclosure is reasonably necessary to:   
(1) investigate, prevent, or take action regarding suspected or actual illegal activities or to assist government enforcement agencies;   
(2) enforce our agreements with you,   
(3) investigate and defend ourselves against any third-party claims or allegations,   
(4) protect the security or integrity of our Service (such as by sharing with companies facing similar threats);   
or (5) exercise or protect the rights and safety of Creativepool, our Members, personnel, or others.   

We attempt to notify Members about legal demands for their personal data when appropriate in our judgment, unless prohibited by law or court order or when the request is an emergency. We may dispute such demands when we believe, in our discretion, that the requests are overbroad, vague or lack proper authority, but we do not promise to challenge every demand.

You can find a wealth of information on Privacy and Data Protection on the ICO's website at https://ico.org.uk/
